<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Woodstock Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-07T07:43:25+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://okckd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Charlie Brown]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Distributed Hash Table (Undone)]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/distributed-hash-table/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/distributed-hash-table</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">ref</a></p>

<h3>Distributed hash table</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Cloud, Grid and Cluster (Undone)]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/cloud-grid-cluster/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/cloud-grid-cluster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9723040/what-is-the-difference-between-cloud-grid-and-cluster">ref</a></p>

<h3>Cluster VS. Grid</h3>

<p><strong><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/9753568">Cluster differs</a> from Cloud and Grid in that</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>a cluster is a group of computers connected by a local area network (LAN)</li>
<li>cloud and grid are more wide scale and can be geographically distributed.</li>
</ol>


<p>Another way to put it is to say that</p>

<ol>
<li>a cluster is tightly coupled</li>
<li>a Grid or a cloud is loosely coupled.</li>
</ol>


<p>Also, <strong>the hardware</strong>:</p>

<ol>
<li>clusters are made up of machines with similar hardware</li>
<li>clouds and grids are made up of machines with possibly very different hardware configurations.</li>
</ol>


<h3>Computer cluster</h3>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_cluster">A computer cluster</a></strong> consists of a set of tightly connected computers that work together as a single system.</p>

<p>Unlike grid computers, computer clusters have each node set to <strong>perform the same task</strong>, controlled and scheduled by software.</p>

<p>In most circumstances, all of the nodes use the <strong>same hardware and OS</strong>. They are connected in <strong>LAN</strong> with each node running its <strong>own piece</strong> of OS.</p>

<p>They are used to improve <strong>performance</strong> and <strong>availability</strong> over that of a single computer, while being more <strong>cost effective</strong>.</p>

<p>Computer clusters emerged as a result of:</p>

<ol>
<li>low-cost microprocessors,</li>
<li>high-speed networks,</li>
<li>software for high-performance distributed computing</li>
</ol>


<h3>Grid computing</h3>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grid_computing">Grid computing</a></strong> is the collection of computer resources from multiple locations to reach a common goal. Each computer have <strong>non-interactive workloads</strong>. It&rsquo;s like a <strong>&ldquo;super virtual computer”</strong> composed of many networked loosely coupled computers acting together to perform large tasks.</p>

<p>Unlike conventional high performance computing systems such as <strong>cluster computing</strong>, grid computers have each node set to <strong>perform a different task</strong>.</p>

<p>Grid computers also tend to be more <strong>geographically dispersed</strong> than cluster computers. Grids are often constructed with general-purpose grid middleware software libraries.</p>

<p>Major disadvantage with Grid Computing is, <strong>if one piece of software on a node fails</strong>, other pieces of the software on the other nodes may fail.</p>

<h3>Cloud computing</h3>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing">Cloud computing</a></strong> is terminology based on utility and <strong>consumption of computing resources</strong>.</p>

<h4>SaaS</h4>

<p>An application doesn&rsquo;t access resources it requires directly, rather it accesses them through <strong>something <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1068133">like a service</a></strong>. Instead of talking to a specific hard drive for storage, and a specific CPU for computation, etc, it talks to some <strong>service that provides these resources</strong>. The service then maps any requests for resources to its physical resources.</p>

<p>The services themselves <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/9753568">have long been referred to</a> as <strong>Software as a Service (SaaS)</strong>. The datacenter hardware and software is what we call <strong>a Cloud</strong>. When a Cloud is made available in a pay-as-you-go manner to the general public, we call it a <strong>Public Cloud</strong>; the service being sold is <strong>Utility Computing</strong>.</p>

<h4>Sharing of Resources</h4>

<p>Usually the service <strong>dynamically allocate resources</strong> to maximize the effectiveness of the shared resources(per users and per demand).</p>

<p>For example, a cloud computer facility that serves European users during European business hours with a specific application (e.g., email) may reallocate the same resources to serve North American users during North America&rsquo;s business hours with a different application (e.g., a web server).</p>

<p>With cloud computing, multiple users can access a single server to retrieve and update their data <strong>without purchasing licenses for different applications</strong>.</p>

<h4>Scalability</h4>

<ol>
<li><p>If an application requires only <strong>a small amount of some resource</strong>, say computation, then the service only allocates a small amount, say a small share on a single physical CPU.</p></li>
<li><p>If the application requires <strong>a large amount of some resource</strong>, then the service allocates that large amount, say a grid of CPUs.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>All the complex handling and coordination is performed <strong>by the service, not the application</strong>. In this way the application can scale well.</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1068133">For example</a> a web site written &ldquo;on the cloud&rdquo; may share a server with many other web sites while it has a low amount of traffic. If it ever has massive amounts of traffic, it may be moved to its own dedicated server, or <strong>grid of servers</strong>. This is all handled <strong>by the cloud service (provider)</strong>, so the application shouldn&rsquo;t have to be modified drastically to cope.</p>

<h4>Other Advantages</h4>

<p>Using Cloud Computing, companies can <a href="http://www.ibeehosting.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-cloud-computing-and-grid-computing.html">scale upto High capacities</a> immediately without investing in new infrastructure, training the people or new software licensing. It is more useful for small and medium scale businesses who wants to outsource their Data Center infrastructure, or some larger companies also prefer if they want to cut down the costs of building data-centers internally in order to get peak load capacity. In short, consumers use what they need and pay accordingly.</p>

<h3>Grid Computing VS. Cloud Computing</h3>

<ol>
<li><p>Grid Computing is the parent of Cloud computing, cloud actually evolves from Grid Computing.</p></li>
<li><p>A cloud would usually use a grid. A grid is not necessarily a cloud.</p></li>
<li><p>Resource distribution: Cloud computing is a centralized model whereas grid computing is a decentralized model where the computation could occur over many administrative domains.</p></li>
<li><p>Ownership: A grid is a collection of computers which is owned by multiple parties in multiple locations and connected together so that users can share the combined power of resources. Whereas a cloud is a collection of computers usually owned by a single party.</p></li>
</ol>


<h4>Examples</h4>

<p>Examples of Clouds: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google App Engine, Dropbox, Gmail, Facebook, Youtube, Rapidshare</p>

<p>Examples of Grids: FutureGrid</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Big Data Storage]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/big-data-storage/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/big-data-storage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mitbbs.com/article/JobHunting/32580869_0.html">ref</a></p>

<h3>Question</h3>

<p><strong>Given 1 trillion messages</strong> on fb and each message has at max 10 words.</p>

<p>How do you build the <strong>index table</strong> and how many machines do you need on the <strong>cluster</strong> to store the index table?</p>

<h3>One possible answer</h3>

<p>Total data = 1 trillion * 10 words * 6 bytes / word = 60TB = one small NetApp box</p>

<p><strong>Index by hashed userid</strong>; will distribute traffic effectively across servers; cache active users recent messages in memory.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.glassdoor.com/Interview/Given-a-set-of-n-jobs-with-start-time-end-time-cost-find-a-subset-so-that-no-2-jobs-overlap-and-the-cost-is-maximum-QTN_440168.htm">Cannot use Netapp box</a>. From what I read in FB engg blog, they have all the info in main memory of server.</p>

<p>Total data = 1 trillion * 10 words * 6 bytes / word = 60TB + 1TB for Indexes.</p>

<p>Considering servers have 64 GB ram. 61 GB usable to store index, 1000 servers.</p>

<h4>For more information</h4>

<p>Read 2 other posts: <strong>[Design] Distributed hash table</strong> and <strong>[Design] Cloud, Grid and Cluster</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Facebook] Write a Json Prettifier]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/Json-prettifier/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/Json-prettifier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.glassdoor.com/Interview/Write-a-function-to-prettify-Json-objects-QTN_151361.htm">link</a></p>

<p>Input:</p>

<pre><code>{"firstName":"John","lastName":"Smith","isAlive":true,"age" :25,"height_cm":167.6,"address":{"streetAddress":"212ndStre et","city":"NewYork","state":"NY","postalCode":"10021-3100" },"phoneNumbers":[{"type":"home","number":"212555-1234"},{" type":"office","number":"646555-4567"}],"children":[],"spou se":null}
</code></pre>

<p>Output:</p>

<pre><code>{
  "firstName": "John",
  "lastName": "Smith",
  "isAlive": true,
  "age": 25,
  "height_cm": 167.6,
  "address": {
    "streetAddress": "21 2nd Street",
    "city": "New York",
    "state": "NY",
    "postalCode": "10021-3100"
  },
  "phoneNumbers": [
    {
      "type": "home",
      "number": "212 555-1234"
    },
    {
      "type": "office",
      "number": "646 555-4567"
    }
  ],
  "children": [],
  "spouse": null
}
</code></pre>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p>Since I did not find anything useful online, I spent an hour writing the following code. These are the things to take into consideration:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Line break</strong> after a comma, a left bracket, or prior to a right bracket. A special pattern is &ldquo;},&rdquo; &ndash; we only do line break once after the comma.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Indentation</strong> is important. We reduce indentation BEFORE we print out a right bracket, butut increase indentation <strong>only AFTER the left bracket</strong>.</p></li>
</ol>


<h3>Code</h3>

<pre><code>public void prettify(String input) throws Exception {

    // observation the rules for Json format:
    // 1. each line end with either a { , or }
    // 2. indentation depends on number of brackets
    int len = input.length();
    int left = 0;
    int right = 0;
    int tab = 0;

    while (left &lt; len) {
        // first, advance right pointer to the next line break point
        while (right &lt; len) {
            if (input.charAt(right) == '}' || input.charAt(right) == ']') {
                // first case, if point to a closing bracket
                tab--;
                // indentation should change right away should we find a
                // closing bracket
                if (right + 1 &lt; len &amp;&amp; input.charAt(right + 1) != ',') {
                    break;
                }
            } else if (input.charAt(right) == ','
                    || input.charAt(right) == '{'
                    || input.charAt(right) == '[') {
                // second case, break at , or {
                break;
            } else if (right + 1 &lt; len
                    &amp;&amp; (input.charAt(right + 1) == '}' || input
                            .charAt(right + 1) == ']')) {
                // third case, break prior to }
                // we need not swap the order of first and third case,
                // because when we found a closing bracket, we need to
                // change indentation right away
                break;
            }
            right++;
        }

        // now print the chars from left pointer to right inclusively
        if (right == len) {
            // end of input
            if (tab != 0) {
                throw new Exception("Json format error!");
            }
            right--;
            // this is for the convenience of printing last line
        }
        printIndentation(tab);
        System.out.println(input.substring(left, right + 1));
        if (input.charAt(right) == '{' || input.charAt(right) == '[') {
            tab++;
        }

        // last, update pointers
        left = ++right;
    }
}

private void printIndentation(int tab) {
    for (int i = 0; i &lt; tab; i++) {
        System.out.print("    ");
    }
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Database Indexing]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/27/database-indexing/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/27/database-indexing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1130">ref 1</a> <a href="http://www.interspire.com/content/2006/02/15/introduction-to-database-indexes/">ref 2</a></p>

<h3>Why Indexing?</h3>

<p>In database disks (we&rsquo;re talking about disk-based storage devices), data is stored as blocks. These blocks are accessed atomically. It&rsquo;s like a linked list with pointers to the blocks.</p>

<p>Because of this, searching in database is linear time. That&rsquo;s why we need indexing.</p>

<p><strong>Indexing is a way of sorting a number of records on multiple fields</strong>. Creating an index on a field in a table creates another data structure which holds the field value, and pointer to the record it relates to. This index structure is then sorted, allowing Binary Searches to be performed on it.</p>

<p>In other words, indexing speed up search.</p>

<h3>Downside</h3>

<p>First disadvantage is <strong>the additional space usage</strong>. For example, in MyISAM engine, indexes are stored together with the data in one table. So the indexing files can quickly reach the size limits if many fields are indexed.</p>

<p>Second disadvantage is that <strong>using too many indexes can actually slow your database down</strong>. Each time a page or database row is updated or removed, the reference or index also has to be updated.</p>

<p>So indexes speed up finding data, but slow down inserting, updating or deleting data.</p>

<h3>Primary keys</h3>

<p><strong>Some fields are automatically indexed</strong>.</p>

<p>A primary key or a field marked as ‘unique’ – for example an email address, a userid or a social security number – are <strong>automatically indexed</strong> so the database can quickly check to make sure that you’re not going to introduce bad data.</p>

<h3>When to use</h3>

<p>Since indexes are <strong>only</strong> used to speed up the searching, it&rsquo;s not wise to have indexing used only for output.</p>

<p><strong>The general rule</strong> is, anything that is used to limit the number of results you’re trying to find. For more details, read <a href="http://www.interspire.com/content/2006/02/15/introduction-to-database-indexes/">ref 2</a>.</p>

<h3>How to create index</h3>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1157">The following</a> is SQL92 standard that&rsquo;s supported by major RDMBSs:</p>

<pre><code>CREATE INDEX [index name] ON [table name] ( [column name] )
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Java OOP] Java Runtime Exception]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/Java-runtime-exception/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/Java-runtime-exception</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Exceptions in Java</h3>

<p>In Java, there are <a href="http://www.tutorialspoint.com/java/java_exceptions.htm">3 categories of exceptions</a>:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>checked exceptions</p>

<ol>
<li>Typically a user error</li>
<li>eg. if a file cannot be found.</li>
<li>These exceptions cannot simply be ignored at the time of compilation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>runtime exceptions (also called un-checked exceptions)</p>

<ol>
<li>exception that could have been avoided by the programmer</li>
<li>eg. NullPointerException</li>
<li>ignored at the time of compilation</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>error</p>

<ol>
<li>These are not exceptions at all</li>
<li>eg. stack overflow occurs</li>
<li>also ignored at the time of compilation</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>


<h4>1. checked exception</h4>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/2190175">A checked exception</a> <strong>must be handled explicitly</strong> by the code (by either putting a try/catch block around the code, or adding a &ldquo;throws&rdquo; clause to the method).</p>

<p>The <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/lang/Exception.html">class Exception</a> and any subclasses that are not also subclasses of RuntimeException are <strong>checked exceptions</strong>.</p>

<p>Note: <strong>java.lang.RuntimeException</strong> is a subclass of <strong>java.lang.Exception</strong>.</p>

<h4>2. un-checked exceptions (RuntimeException)</h4>

<p>A un-checked exception <strong>does not need</strong> to be explicitly handled.</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/lang/RuntimeException.html">RuntimeException</a> and its subclasses are <strong>unchecked exceptions</strong>.</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/2190177">Generally</a> RuntimeExceptions <strong>can be prevented</strong> programmatically. E.g NullPointerException, ArrayIndexOutOfBoundException. If you check for null before calling any method, NullPointerException would never occur. Similarly ArrayIndexOutOfBoundException would never occur if you check the index first. RuntimeException are not checked by the compiler, so it is clean code.</p>

<p>The runtime exception classes <strong><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/2190659">are exempted</a> from compile-time checking</strong>, since the compiler cannot establish that run-time exceptions cannot occur.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Ruby] Endless Error With Gem Dependencies]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/Endless-error-gem-dependencies/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/Endless-error-gem-dependencies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The problem</h3>

<p>In setting up the octopress environment, we need to install dependencies like this:</p>

<pre><code>gem install bundler
bundle install
</code></pre>

<p>First line simply installs bundler (a Ruby dependency manager). The second line is where you might face problems:</p>

<blockquote><p>bundle install</p>

<p><a href="http://bundler.io/man/bundle-install.1.html">Install the dependencies</a> specified in your Gemfile</p></blockquote>

<p>Look at the Gemfile in your octopress folder, it looks like <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/blob/master/Gemfile">this</a>:</p>

<pre><code>source "https://rubygems.org"

group :development do
  gem 'rake', '~&gt; 10.0'
  gem 'jekyll', '~&gt; 2.0'
  gem 'octopress-hooks', '~&gt; 2.2'
  gem 'octopress-date-format', '~&gt; 2.0'
  gem 'jekyll-sitemap'
  gem 'rdiscount', '~&gt; 2.0'
  gem 'RedCloth', '~&gt; 4.2.9'
  gem 'haml', '~&gt; 4.0'
  gem 'compass', '~&gt; 1.0.1'
  gem 'sass-globbing', '~&gt; 1.0.0'
  gem 'rubypants', '~&gt; 0.2.0'
  gem 'rb-fsevent', '~&gt; 0.9'
  gem 'stringex', '~&gt; 1.4.0'
end

gem 'sinatra', '~&gt; 1.4.2'
</code></pre>

<p>When I do &lsquo;bundle install&rsquo;:</p>

<pre><code>$ bundle install
Fetching gem metadata from https://rubygems.org/........
Resolving dependencies...

Gem::RemoteFetcher::FetchError: SSL_connect returned=1 errno=0 state=SSLv3 read
server certificate B: certificate verify failed (https://rubygems.org/gems/rake-
10.4.2.gem)
An error occurred while installing rake (10.4.2), and Bundler cannot continue.
Make sure that `gem install rake -v '10.4.2'` succeeds before bundling.
</code></pre>

<p>It shows the gem &lsquo;rake&rsquo; is missing. So I did as I was instrcucted to. I type <strong>gem install rake -v &lsquo;10.4.2&rsquo;</strong> into command line, and execute. Again, I was told another gem missing. I kept doing this, until I found this is an endless procedure:</p>

<pre><code>$ bundle install
Fetching gem metadata from https://rubygems.org/.......
Using rake 10.3.2
Using RedCloth 4.2.9
Using blankslate 2.1.2.4

Gem::RemoteFetcher::FetchError: SSL_connect returned=1 errno=0 state=SSLv3 read
server certificate B: certificate verify failed (https://rubygems.org/gems/timer
s-1.1.0.gem)
An error occurred while installing timers (1.1.0), and Bundler cannot continue.
Make sure that `gem install timers -v '1.1.0'` succeeds before bundling.
</code></pre>

<p>Something is very wrong with the execution of &lsquo;bundle install&rsquo;.</p>

<h3>The solution</h3>

<p>Until I found <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/15529451/octopress-installation-stops-during-bundle-install">this post</a>, I was hopelessly searching and learning Ruby gems and related things.</p>

<p>I fact, I just deleted 1 letter by changing <strong>source &ldquo;<a href="https://rubygems.org">https://rubygems.org</a>&rdquo;</strong> to <strong>source &ldquo;<a href="http://rubygems.org">http://rubygems.org</a>&rdquo;</strong> at line 1 of Gemfile in octopress folder.</p>

<p>Then, everything is fine:</p>

<pre><code>$ bundle install
Fetching gem metadata from http://rubygems.org/........
Resolving dependencies....
Installing rake 10.4.2
Using RedCloth 4.2.9
Using blankslate 2.1.2.4
Installing hitimes 1.2.2
Installing timers 4.0.1
Installing celluloid 0.16.0
Installing chunky_png 1.3.3
Installing fast-stemmer 1.0.2
Installing classifier-reborn 2.0.2
Installing coffee-script-source 1.8.0
Installing execjs 2.2.2
Installing coffee-script 2.3.0
Installing colorator 0.1
Installing multi_json 1.10.1
Installing sass 3.4.9
Installing compass-core 1.0.1
Installing compass-import-once 1.0.5
Installing rb-fsevent 0.9.4
Installing ffi 1.9.6
Installing rb-inotify 0.9.5
Installing compass 1.0.1
Installing tilt 1.4.1
Installing haml 4.0.6
Installing jekyll-coffeescript 1.0.1
Installing jekyll-gist 1.1.0
Installing jekyll-paginate 1.1.0
Installing jekyll-sass-converter 1.3.0
Installing listen 2.8.4
Installing jekyll-watch 1.2.0
Installing kramdown 1.5.0
Installing liquid 2.6.1
Installing mercenary 0.3.5
Installing posix-spawn 0.3.9
Installing yajl-ruby 1.1.0
Installing pygments.rb 0.6.0
Installing redcarpet 3.2.2
Installing safe_yaml 1.0.4
Installing parslet 1.5.0
Installing toml 0.1.2
Installing jekyll 2.5.3
Installing jekyll-sitemap 0.7.0
Installing octopress-hooks 2.2.3
Installing octopress-date-format 2.0.2
Installing rack 1.6.0
Installing rack-protection 1.5.3
Installing rdiscount 2.1.7.1
Installing rubypants 0.2.0
Installing sass-globbing 1.0.0
Installing sinatra 1.4.5
Installing stringex 1.4.0
Using bundler 1.7.9
Your bundle is complete!
Use `bundle show [gemname]` to see where a bundled gem is installed.
Post-install message from compass:
    Compass is charityware. If you love it, please donate on our behalf at http:
//umdf.org/compass Thanks!
Post-install message from haml:

HEADS UP! Haml 4.0 has many improvements, but also has changes that may break
your application:

* Support for Ruby 1.8.6 dropped
* Support for Rails 2 dropped
* Sass filter now always outputs &lt;style&gt; tags
* Data attributes are now hyphenated, not underscored
* html2haml utility moved to the html2haml gem
* Textile and Maruku filters moved to the haml-contrib gem

For more info see:

http://rubydoc.info/github/haml/haml/file/CHANGELOG.md
</code></pre>

<p>I guess this is because my network security settings, but I do not know. If you are facing the same issue, I hope my solution helped. Or if you know the reason, please tell me by leaving a comment below. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Java OOP] Override/overload Java Main Method]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/overload-override-java-main-method/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/overload-override-java-main-method</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Can we overload main method in Java?</h3>

<p>Can. But only <strong>public static void main(String[] args)</strong> will be used when <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3759315/can-we-overload-the-main-method-in-java">your class is launched by the JVM</a>.</p>

<p>You can call other <strong>main() method</strong> yourself from code.</p>

<p>Eg.</p>

<pre><code>class Simple{  
  public static void main(int a){  
  System.out.println(a);  
  }  

  public static void main(String args[]){  
  System.out.println("main() method invoked");  
  main(10);  
  }  
}
</code></pre>

<p>output:</p>

<pre><code>main() method invoked
10
</code></pre>

<h3>Can we override main method in Java?</h3>

<p>No.</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9083876/override-main-method">MAIN is a class method</a>. Hence, it does not makes sense to &ldquo;override&rdquo; it (or any static method). The concept of &ldquo;overriding&rdquo; is only for instance methods.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Java OOP] Common Root of Java Classes]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/common-root-java-class/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/common-root-java-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Common Root Class</h3>

<p><strong>java.lang.Object</strong>, <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/lang/Object.html">link</a></p>

<p>All Java classes are derived from this <a href="http://www.ntu.edu.sg/home/ehchua/programming/java/J3b_OOPInheritancePolymorphism.html">common root class</a>, that defines common behaviors.</p>

<p>Common behaviors include multi-threading and garbage collector etc.</p>

<h4>Some methods</h4>

<p><a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/IandI/objectclass.html">ref</a></p>

<p>protected Object clone() throws CloneNotSupportedException</p>

<blockquote><p>Creates and returns a copy of this object.</p></blockquote>

<p>public boolean equals(Object obj)</p>

<blockquote><p>Indicates whether some other object is &ldquo;equal to&rdquo; this one.</p></blockquote>

<p>protected void finalize() throws Throwable</p>

<blockquote><p>Called by the garbage collector on an object when garbage collection determines that there are no more references to the object</p></blockquote>

<p>public final Class getClass()</p>

<blockquote><p>Returns the runtime class of an object.</p></blockquote>

<p>public int hashCode()</p>

<blockquote><p>Returns a hash code value for the object.</p></blockquote>

<p>public String toString()</p>

<blockquote><p>Returns a string representation of the object.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Sync-related methods</h3>

<p>The notify, notifyAll, and wait methods of Object all play a part in synchronizing the activities of independently running threads in a program.</p>

<pre><code>public final void notify()
public final void notifyAll()
public final void wait()
public final void wait(long timeout)
public final void wait(long timeout, int nanos)
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Java OOP] Interface Extend Another Interface]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/can-interface-extend-interface/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/can-interface-extend-interface</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Can an interface extend another interface in Java?</h3>

<p>Yes. Just remember that you should implement the methods in <a href="http://www.programmerinterview.com/index.php/java-questions/java-can-an-interface-extend-another-interface/">both interfaces</a>.</p>

<p>Example in Java source code <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/List.html">link1</a>, <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/Collection.html">link2</a>:</p>

<pre><code>public interface List&lt;E&gt; extends Collection&lt;E&gt; {

}

public interface Collection&lt;E&gt; extends Iterable&lt;E&gt; {

}
</code></pre>

<p>In conclusion, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/19546357/can-an-interface-extend-multiple-interfaces-in-java">ref</a></p>

<p>An interface can extend multiple interfaces.</p>

<p>A class can implement multiple interfaces.</p>

<p>However, a class can only extend a single class.</p>

<h4>a special case</h4>

<pre><code>interface A
{
    void test();
}

interface B 
{
    void test();
}

class C implements A, B
{
    @Override
    public void test() {

    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Well, a single implementation works for the both methods. This implementation works no problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Ruby] RubyGems, Gem, Gemfile and Bundler]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/RubyGems-gem-other/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/RubyGems-gem-other</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometme I found the different concepts in Ruby very confusing for beginners. So I write this post to explain some terminologies in ruby setup.</p>

<h3>RubyGems (tool)</h3>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RubyGems">RubyGems</a></strong> is a package manager for the Ruby programming language.</p>

<p>It is a tool to manage the installation of gems, and a server for distributing them.</p>

<p>RubyGems is very similar to apt-get, portage, and yum in functionality.</p>

<h3>gem (command)</h3>

<p>&lsquo;gem&rsquo; command allows you to interact with RubyGems. It is used build, upload, download, and install Gem packages.</p>

<p>Installation:</p>

<pre><code>gem install mygem
</code></pre>

<p>Uninstallation:</p>

<pre><code>gem uninstall mygem
</code></pre>

<p>Listing installed gems:</p>

<pre><code>gem list --local
</code></pre>

<p>Listing available gems, e.g.:</p>

<pre><code>gem list --remote
</code></pre>

<h3>Gemfile (text file)</h3>

<p><a href="http://bundler.io/man/gemfile.5.html">A Gemfile</a> describes the gem dependencies required to execute associated Ruby code.</p>

<p>It is placed in the root of the directory containing the associated code.</p>

<p>A Gemfile is evaluated as Ruby code, in a context which makes available a number of methods used to describe the gem requirements.</p>

<h3>gem (program)</h3>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5233924/what-is-a-ruby-gem">ref1</a>, <a href="http://guides.rubygems.org/what-is-a-gem/">ref2</a></p>

<p>A gem is a module/Library that you can install and use in every project on your server.</p>

<p>Each gem has a <strong>name, version, and platform</strong>. For example, <strong>rake gem</strong> has a 10.3.2 version on platform Ruby.</p>

<p>Inside a gems are the following components:</p>

<ol>
<li>Code (including tests and supporting utilities)</li>
<li>Documentation</li>
<li>gemspec</li>
</ol>


<p>Standard code structure:</p>

<pre><code>% tree freewill
freewill/
├── bin/
│   └── freewill
├── lib/
│   └── freewill.rb
├── test/
│   └── test_freewill.rb
├── README
├── Rakefile
└── freewill.gemspec
</code></pre>

<h3>Bundler (dependency manager)</h3>

<p><a href="http://bundler.io/">ref</a></p>

<p>Bundler manages an application&rsquo;s dependencies.</p>

<p>Bundler provides a consistent environment for Ruby projects by tracking and installing the exact gems and versions that are needed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Facebook] Maximum Sum Such That No Two Elements Are Adjacent]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/Maximum-sum-no-adjacent/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/Maximum-sum-no-adjacent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.geeksforgeeks.org/maximum-sum-such-that-no-two-elements-are-adjacent/">link</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Given an array of positive numbers, find the maximum sum of a subsequence that no 2 numbers should be adjacent.</p>

<p>Eg. (3, 2, 7, 10) should return 13 (3+10)</p>

<p>Eg. (3, 2, 5, 10, 7) should return 15 (3+5+7).</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p>It is an modified version of &ldquo;max sum subsequence&rdquo;. Answer given on <a href="http://www.geeksforgeeks.org/maximum-sum-such-that-no-two-elements-are-adjacent/">gfg</a> is:</p>

<blockquote><p>Loop for all elements in arr[] and maintain two sums &lsquo;incl&rsquo; and &lsquo;excl&rsquo; where:</p>

<p>incl = Max sum including the previous element</p>

<p>excl = Max sum excluding the previous element</p></blockquote>

<h3>Code</h3>

<p><strong>written by me</strong></p>

<pre><code>public int solve(int[] A) {
    if (A == null || A.length == 0) {
        return 0;
    } else if (A.length == 1) {
        return A[0];
    } else if (A.length == 2) {
        return Math.max(A[0], A[1]);
    }

    // prePreMax is the max non-adjacency sequence ending 2 position ahead
    // preMax is the max non-adjacency sequence ending 1 position ahead
    int prePreMax = A[0];
    int preMax = A[1];
    int ans = 0;

    for (int i = 2; i &lt; A.length; i++) {
        ans = Math.max(ans, prePreMax + A[i]);
        // set the 2 variables: prePreMax, preMax
        int temp = preMax;
        preMax = Math.max(0, prePreMax + A[i]);
        prePreMax = Math.max(prePreMax, temp);
    }
    return ans;
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Java OOP] Discussion of Polymorphism]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/Discussion-of-Polymorphism/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/Discussion-of-Polymorphism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Polymorphism</h3>

<p>Polymorphism is to <a href="http://javarevisited.blogspot.sg/2011/08/what-is-polymorphism-in-java-example.html">use common interface</a> instead of concrete implementation while coding.</p>

<p>When we program for interface our code is capable of handling any new requirement or enhancement arise in near future due to new implementation of our common interface. If we don&rsquo;t use common interface and rely on concrete implementation, we always need to change and duplicate most of our code to support new implementation.</p>

<p>The most common use of polymorphism in OOP occurs when a parent class reference is used to refer to a child class object.</p>

<h3>Example</h3>

<p>Example of Bicycle class given on <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/IandI/polymorphism.html">official oracle website</a>:</p>

<pre><code>public class Bicycle{
    public void printDescription(){
        System.out.println("\nBike is " + "in gear " + this.gear
            + " with a cadence of " + this.cadence +
            " and travelling at a speed of " + this.speed + ". ");
    }
}

public class MountainBike extends Bicycle {
    private String suspension;

    public void printDescription() {
        super.printDescription();
        System.out.println("The " + "MountainBike has a" +
            getSuspension() + " suspension.");
    }
}

public class RoadBike extends Bicycle{
    private int tireWidth;

    public void printDescription(){
        super.printDescription();
        System.out.println("The RoadBike" + " has " + getTireWidth() +
            " MM tires.");
    }
}

public class TestBikes {
    public static void main(String[] args){
        Bicycle bike01, bike02, bike03;

        bike01 = new Bicycle(20, 10, 1);
        bike02 = new MountainBike(20, 10, 5, "Dual");
        bike03 = new RoadBike(40, 20, 8, 23);

        bike01.printDescription();
        bike02.printDescription();
        bike03.printDescription();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>The output:</p>

<pre><code>Bike is in gear 1 with a cadence of 20 and travelling at a speed of 10. 

Bike is in gear 5 with a cadence of 20 and travelling at a speed of 10. 
The MountainBike has a Dual suspension.

Bike is in gear 8 with a cadence of 40 and travelling at a speed of 20. 
The RoadBike has 23 MM tires.
</code></pre>

<p>Referring to the same page, <strong>JVM calls the appropriate method for the object that is referred to in each variable</strong>. It does not call the method that is defined by the variable&rsquo;s type.</p>

<h3>Another example</h3>

<p>Cylinder is a subclass of Circle. We can say that Cylinder &ldquo;is-a&rdquo; Circle.</p>

<p>We can create an instance of Cylinder, and assign it to a Circle reference:</p>

<blockquote><p>Circle c1 = new Cylinder();</p></blockquote>

<p>You can invoke all the methods defined in the Circle class, but <strong>you cannot invoke methods defined in the Cylinder class</strong>. c1 is a reference to the Circle class, which does not know about the methods defined in the subclass Cylinder.</p>

<p><strong>The reference c1, however, retains its internal identity</strong>. Since Cylinder overrides getArea() method, calling c1.getArea() will invokes the overridden version defined in subclass Cylinder, instead of in Circle. This is because c1 is holding a Cylinder object internally.</p>

<p>The code is below:</p>

<pre><code>public class PolymorphismSubstitutabilityDemo {

    public static void main(String[] args) {
        Circle c1 = new Cylinder(1, "white", 10);
        System.out.println(c1.getClass());
        System.out.println(c1.getRadius());
        System.out.println(c1.getColor());
        System.out.println(c1.getArea());
    }
}

class Circle {
    int radius;
    String color;

    public Circle(int a, String b) {
        this.radius = a;
        this.color = b;
    }

    public int getRadius() {
        return radius;
    }

    public String getColor() {
        return color;
    }

    public double getArea() {
        return 3.14159 * Math.pow(radius, 2);
    }
}

class Cylinder extends Circle {
    int height;

    public Cylinder(int a, String b, int c) {
        super(a, b);
        this.height = c;
    }

    public int getHeight() {
        return height;
    }

    public double getArea() {
        return super.getArea() * height;
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>The output of execution:</p>

<pre><code>class Cylinder
1
white
31.4159
</code></pre>

<h3>Summary:</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.ntu.edu.sg/home/ehchua/programming/java/J3b_OOPInheritancePolymorphism.html">ref</a></p>

<ol>
<li><p>A subclass instance can be assigned (substituted) to a superclass&#8217; reference.</p></li>
<li><p>Once substituted, we can invoke methods defined in the superclass; we cannot invoke methods defined in the subclass.</p></li>
<li><p>However, if the subclass overrides inherited methods from the superclass, the subclass (overridden) versions will be invoked.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Facebook] Binary Search Tree 3Sum (Undone)]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/Binary-Search-Tree-3Sum/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/Binary-Search-Tree-3Sum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p>DLL &ndash; <a href="http://www.geeksforgeeks.org/find-if-there-is-a-triplet-in-bst-that-adds-to-0/">link</a></p>

<p>Inorder &ndash; <a href="http://www.geeksforgeeks.org/find-a-pair-with-given-sum-in-bst/">link</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Given a BST, write a function that returns true if there is a triplet that sums to 0, returns false otherwise.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p>We will solve the question just like we do <strong>[LeetCode 15] 3Sum</strong>. What is missing is an random access of tree nodes, like we have in array.</p>

<p>In fact, we do not need random access. Tree traversal (one after another in sequence) would be good enough.</p>

<p>Now there&rsquo;re 2 solution. <strong>First is to convert the tree to Double-linked list</strong>, then do 3Sum. The conversion takes O(n) time and O(logn) extra space, and 3Sum take O(n<sup>2</sup>). however doing this modifies the original tree.</p>

<p><strong>Second solution is to to inorder traversal and reversed inorder traversal</strong>. This is a better solution, personally. And the time and space used is same.</p>

<h3>Code</h3>

<p><strong>DLL way, written by me</strong></p>

<pre><code>public void findTriplet(TreeNode root, int target) {
    TreeNode[] dll = convertToDll(root);
    TreeNode head = dll[0];
    TreeNode tail = dll[1];
    // note that the bst inorder dll should already in sorted by value
    TreeNode first = head;
    while (first.right != null) {
        TreeNode left = first.right;
        TreeNode right = tail;
        while (left.val &lt; right.val) {
            int diff = first.val + left.val + right.val - target;
            if (diff == 0) {
                System.out.println("Found triplet: " + first.val + " "
                        + left.val + " " + right.val + " for sum of "
                        + target);
            }
            if (diff &lt;= 0) {
                left = left.right;
            }
            if (diff &gt;= 0) {
                right = right.left;
            }
        }
        first = first.right;
    }
}

private TreeNode[] convertToDll(TreeNode node) {
    TreeNode[] ans = new TreeNode[2];
    // do the left side of node
    if (node.left == null) {
        ans[0] = node;
    } else {
        TreeNode[] preAns = convertToDll(node.left);
        ans[0] = preAns[0];
        node.left = preAns[1];
        preAns[1].right = node;
    }
    // do the right side of node
    if (node.right == null) {
        ans[1] = node;
    } else {
        TreeNode[] postAns = convertToDll(node.right);
        ans[1] = postAns[1];
        node.right = postAns[0];
        postAns[0].left = node;
    }
    return ans;
}
</code></pre>

<p><strong>inorder way</strong></p>

<p>undone</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Facebook] Print a Binary Tree in Vertical Order]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/Print-Binary-Tree-Vertically/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/Print-Binary-Tree-Vertically</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.geeksforgeeks.org/print-binary-tree-vertical-order/">link</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Given a binary tree, print it vertically. The following example illustrates vertical order traversal.</p></blockquote>

<pre><code>           1
        /    \
       2      3
      / \    / \
     4   5  6   7
             \   \
              8   9 

The output of print this tree vertically will be:
4
2
1 5 6
3 8
7
9 
</code></pre>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<ol>
<li><p>Traverse the tree once and get the minimum and maximum horizontal distance with respect to root.</p></li>
<li><p>Iterate for each vertical line at distance minimum to maximum from root.</p></li>
</ol>


<h3>Code</h3>

<p><strong>written by me</strong></p>

<pre><code>public List&lt;List&lt;Integer&gt;&gt; printVertically(TreeNode root) {
    List&lt;List&lt;Integer&gt;&gt; ans = new ArrayList&lt;List&lt;Integer&gt;&gt;();

    // 1. find the range of left bound and right bound
    int[] range = new int[2];
    findRange(root, range, 0);

    // 2. calculate number of columns in the result
    int rootIndex = 0 - range[0];
    int columns = range[1] - range[0] + 1;
    for (int i = 0; i &lt; columns; i++) {
        ans.add(new ArrayList&lt;Integer&gt;());
    }

    // 3. fill in vertically in a recursive manner
    fillNode(ans, root, rootIndex);

    return ans;
}

private void fillNode(List&lt;List&lt;Integer&gt;&gt; ans, TreeNode node, int index) {
    if (node == null) {
        return;
    }
    ans.get(index).add(node.val);
    fillNode(ans, node.left, index - 1);
    fillNode(ans, node.right, index + 1);
}

private void findRange(TreeNode node, int[] range, int position) {
    if (node == null) {
        return;
    }
    if (position &lt; range[0]) {
        range[0] = position;
    }
    if (position &gt; range[1]) {
        range[1] = position;
    }
    findRange(node.left, range, position - 1);
    findRange(node.right, range, position + 1);
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Epic] Patient Disease Data Structure]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/patient-disease-data-structure/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/patient-disease-data-structure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.mitbbs.com/article_t0/JobHunting/32844253.html">link</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Suppose N patients and M diseases. N is sufficiently large number and M is
relatively small, say 30-ish. Each patient can have possible 0 to M kinds of
diseases.</p>

<p>Given one patient’s name, show me a list of similar patients sharing same
deseases within 2-3 seconds.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p><strong>Use 1 bit to represent a disease</strong>. So every patient&rsquo;s conditin can be put into an integer of 32 bits.</p>

<p>How do we calculate the similarity of 2 patients?</p>

<p>Refer to <strong>[CC150v5] 5.5 Calculate Bits Conversion Required</strong> for a special bit operation (remove last &lsquo;1&rsquo; from bit):</p>

<blockquote><p>c = c &amp; (c &ndash; l) clears the least significant bit of &lsquo;1&rsquo;.</p>

<p>Keep doing this until all &lsquo;1&rsquo;s are cleared.</p></blockquote>

<p>For each patient, we simply calculate the XOR and count &lsquo;1&rsquo;s.</p>

<h3>Code</h3>

<p>no code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Leetcode] Leetcode Fourth Round]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/Leetcode-fourth/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/12/01/Leetcode-fourth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>Days:        01/12/2014 - now
Submission:  
Pass:        

Submit/day:  
Pass/day:    

Pass/submit: 
</code></pre>

<h3>Easy</h3>

<ol>
<li>[LeetCode 1] Two Sum</li>
<li>[LeetCode 5] Longest Palindromic Substring</li>
<li>[LeetCode 6] ZigZag Conversion</li>
<li>[LeetCode 7] Reverse Integer</li>
<li>[LeetCode 12] Integer to Roman</li>
<li>[LeetCode 16] 3Sum Closest</li>
<li>[LeetCode 18] 4Sum</li>
<li>[LeetCode 19] Remove Nth Node From End of List</li>
<li>[LeetCode 23] Merge K Sorted Lists</li>
<li>[LeetCode 25] Reverse Nodes in k-Groups</li>
<li>[LeetCode 27] Remove Element</li>
<li>[LeetCode 30] Substring With Concatenation of All Words</li>
<li>[LeetCode 32] Longest Valid Parentheses</li>
<li>[LeetCode 36] Valid Sudoku</li>
<li>[LeetCode 41] First Missing Positive</li>
<li>[LeetCode 42] Trapping Rain Water</li>
<li>[LeetCode 45] Jump Game II</li>
<li>[LeetCode 50] Pow(x, N)</li>
<li>[LeetCode 55] Jump Game</li>
<li>[LeetCode 72] Edit Distance</li>
<li>[LeetCode 79] Word Search</li>
<li>[LeetCode 80] Remove Duplicates From Sorted Array II</li>
<li>[LeetCode 94] Binary Tree Inorder Traversal</li>
<li>[LeetCode 142] Linked List Cycle II</li>
</ol>


<h3>Difficult</h3>

<ol>
<li>[LeetCode 3] Longest Substring Without Repeating Characters</li>
<li>[LeetCode 4] Median of Two Sorted Arrays</li>
<li>[LeetCode 10] Regular Expression Matching</li>
<li>[LeetCode 15] 3Sum</li>
<li>[LeetCode 29] Divide Two Integers</li>
<li>[LeetCode 37] Sudoku Solver</li>
<li>[LeetCode 44] Wildcard Matching</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Google] Code a HashMap]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/Code-a-hashmap/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/Code-a-hashmap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.glassdoor.com/Interview/Code-a-hashmap-which-you-would-be-happy-to-place-into-a-production-environment-QTN_725885.htm">link</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Code a hashmap which you would be happy to place into a production environment.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p>We already write 2 post before:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>[Question] Implement a HashMap</strong></p></li>
<li><p><strong>[CC150v5] 8.10 Implement a Hashmap</strong></p></li>
</ol>


<p>But still, this is not an easy question when asked at an interview. It won&rsquo;t harm to do a little recap:</p>

<ol>
<li>The basic structure is an array. It can be:

<ol>
<li>An array of linked nodes (with a next pointer).</li>
<li>An array of linked list.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>There should be a hash function.</li>
<li>There should be a function to convert the hash value to corresponding array index.</li>
<li>Remember there&rsquo;s <strong>a concept of Load factor</strong>. It means to what percentage the hashmap is filled.</li>
<li>h &amp; (length – 1) means h % length, which maps a hashcode to an array index.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[CC150v5] 18.7 Longest Word Made From Other Words]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/10/02/longest-word-made-from-other/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/10/02/longest-word-made-from-other</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<blockquote><p>Given a list of words, write a program to find the longest word made of other words in the list.</p>

<p>EXAMPLE</p>

<p>Input: cat, banana, dog, nana, walk, walker, dogwalker</p>

<p>Output: dogwalker</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p><strong>Search it recursively from longest to shortest</strong>. Use HashSet to help us search for words quickly.</p>

<p>This question might look difficult at first, it&rsquo;s actually a very classical recursive search.</p>

<h3>Code</h3>

<pre><code>public static void printLongestWord(String[] arr) {
    Arrays.sort(arr, new LengthComparator());
    HashSet&lt;String&gt; set = new HashSet&lt;String&gt;();
    for (String str : arr) {
        set.add(str);
    }
    for (String word : arr) {
        if (canDivide(word, 0, set)) {
            System.out.println(word);
            return;
        }
    }
    System.out.println("can not find such word");
}

private static boolean canDivide(String word, int from, HashSet&lt;String&gt; set) {
    if (from == word.length()) {
        return true;
    }
    for (int i = from; i &lt; word.length(); i++) {
        String str = word.substring(from, i + 1);
        if (from == 0 &amp;&amp; i == word.length() - 1) {
            continue;
        } else if (!set.contains(str)) {
            continue;
        }
        if (canDivide(word, i + 1, set)) {
            return true;
        }
    }
    return false;
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[CC150v5] 17.14 Optimal Way to Unconcatenate Doc]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/optimal-unconcatenate-doc/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/optimal-unconcatenate-doc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Question</h3>

<blockquote><p>Given a lengthy document without spaces, punctuation, and capitalization:</p>

<p>eg: iresetthecomputeritstilldidntboot</p>

<p>Now add back in the punctation and capitalization.</p>

<p>Most of the words will be in a dictionary, but some strings, like proper names, will not. Given a dictionary (a list of words), design an algorithm to find the optimal way of &ldquo;unconcatenating&rdquo; a sequence of words (by minimizing unrecognized sequences of characters).</p>

<p>For example, the string &ldquo;jesslookedjustliketimherbrother&rdquo; would be optimally parsed as &ldquo;JESS looked just like TIM her brother&rdquo;. This parsing has seven unrecognized characters, which we have capitalized for clarity.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Solution</h3>

<p>The solution given in the book is very hard to understand. It uses HashMap to memorize the previous result.</p>

<p>After long time of struggle, I finally solved it with traditional DP approach. The key idea is to consider: &ldquo;<strong>whether I insert a space after this char, or not</strong>&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The code is concise and easy to read.</p>

<h3>Code</h3>

<pre><code>public static int parse(String doc, Trie dict) {
    int len = doc.length();
    int[] dp = new int[len + 1];
    // dp[i] denotes the number of special chars in first i chars of docs
    for (int i = 1; i &lt;= len; i++) {
        dp[i] =  Integer.MAX_VALUE;
        for (int j = 0; j &lt; i; j++) {
            String str = doc.substring(j, i);
            if (dict.contains(str, true)) {
                // consider (i to j) a valid word
                dp[i] = Math.min(dp[i], dp[j]);
            } else {
                // consider (i to j) special chars
                dp[i] = Math.min(dp[i], dp[j] + i - j);
            }
        }
    }
    return dp[len];
}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
