<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Woodstock Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-30T22:15:03+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://okckd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Charlie Brown]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] DNS Communication Protocol]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/12/DNS-communication-protocol/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/12/DNS-communication-protocol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Question 

> What protocol is used for communicating with a DNS? 

### Answer

[Domain Name System](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System) (DNS) is a hierarchical distributed naming system for computers, services, or any resource connected to the Internet or a private network. It associates various information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities. Most prominently, it translates easily memorized domain names to the numerical IP addresses needed for the purpose of locating computer services and devices worldwide. The Domain Name System is an essential component of the functionality of the Internet. 

[DNS primarily uses](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System#Protocol_transport) __User Datagram Protocol (UDP)__ on port number 53 to serve requests. 

DNS queries consist of a single UDP request from the client followed by a single UDP reply from the server. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Leader Election]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/Leader-election/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/Leader-election</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Question 

(this question is from MIT handouts B)

> Describe a technique to identify a "leader" among a group of 10 identical servers that are all connected to every other server. 

> There are no prior distinguishing characteristics of any of them and the same program to identify the leader starts running on all of them at the same time. After an answer is given, ask how much network traffic it requires and, if "ties" are possible, ask how you can break ties.

### Leader Election 

__[Leader Election](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leader_election)__ is the process of designating a single process as the organizer of some task distributed among several computers. After running this algorithm, each node throughout the network recognizes a unique node as the task leader. 

The good answer would be: 

Have each server wait a random amount of time and then say "I'm it." The "I'm it" __announcement is time‐stamped__, and the computer that __time‐stamped its announcement first__ is elected the leader. 

This approach requires sending out 9 messages. __If there is a tie__, the computers can repeat the procedure.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Listener / Observer Pattern]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/Listener-Observer-pattern/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/Listener-Observer-pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Observer pattern

__[The observer pattern](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Observer_pattern)__ is a software design pattern in which an object(subject) maintains a list of dependents(observers), and notifies them automatically of any state changes (usually by calling one of their methods). 

The Observer pattern is mainly used to implement distributed event handling systems. It's also a key part in MVC architectural. 

### Example

A mailing list example. 

Each student in the mailing list would be a listener/observer, and teacher would be announcer/subject. 

So in the code, there's a Listener Interface that all students implement. There's a update() method in the interface, where each student define their own implementation. 

Teacher would keep a list of Listeners. When there's any news, teacher would call update() on each object. 

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] Multithreading - Deadlock Prevention]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/01/Multithreading-deadlock-prevention/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/09/01/Multithreading-deadlock-prevention</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Question

> How to prevent deadlock? (question from MIT handouts 1)

### Analysis

Preventing one of the 4 conditions will prevent deadlock: 

1. Removing the __mutual exclusion condition__, but not very possible. 

1. The __hold and wait__ conditions may be removed by requiring processes to request all the resources they will need before starting up. 

1. The __no preemption condition__ may also be difficult or impossible to avoid as a process has to be able to have a resource for a certain amount of time, or the processing outcome may be inconsistent or thrashing may occur. 

1. The final condition is the __circular wait condition__. Approaches that avoid circular waits include disabling interrupts during critical sections and using a hierarchy to determine a partial ordering of resources. 

### Answer

__Assign an order to our locks__ (require that the locks always acquired in order). 

This prevent 2 thread waiting to get the resource in each other's hand. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Design] HTTP Cookie]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/Http-cookie/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-28T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/Http-cookie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### First Word

A cookie is __a small text file__ that is stored by a browser on the user’s machine. Cookies are plain text; they contain no executable code. 

Every time the user loads the website, the __browser sends the cookie back to the server__ to notify the website of the user's previous activity. 

1. Stateful information

	Such as shopping cart

1. browsing activity

	Such as log in, which button is clicked, and which page is visited

### Security

A secure cookie will only be sent to the server when a request is made using SSL and the HTTPS protocol. However, the entire mechanism is inherently insecure. 

The cookie just contains data and __isn’t harmful__ in and of itself. However, tracking cookies and especially third-party tracking cookies are commonly used as ways to compile long-term records of individuals' browsing history, which is a potential privacy concern. 

### Types of HTTP Cookie

Common cookie types: 

#### Session cookie

It's __while browsing__. (Normally) deleted by browser when the user closes the browser.
	
#### Persistent cookie

Max-age 1 year. The value set in that cookie would be sent back to the server every time the user visited the server. Also called __tracking cookies__

#### Secure cookie

The secure attribute is enabled, and is only used via HTTPS. 

#### Third-party cookie

__First-party cookies__ are cookies that belong to the same domain that is shown in the browser's address bar. __Third-party cookies__ are cookies that belong to domains different from the one shown in the address bar. 

It opens up the potential for __tracking the user's browsing history__. An example of 3rd-party: 

> As an example, suppose a user visits www.example1.com. This web site contains an advert from ad.foxytracking.com, which, when downloaded, sets a cookie belonging to the advert's domain (ad.foxytracking.com). Then, the user visits another website, www.example2.com, which also contains an advert from ad.foxytracking.com, and which also sets a cookie belonging to that domain (ad.foxytracking.com). Eventually, both of these cookies will be sent to the advertiser when loading their ads or visiting their website. The advertiser can then use these cookies to build up a browsing history of the user across all the websites that have ads from this advertiser.

#### One more thing

Nowadays ther'e a new kind of __HttpOnly cookie__ (used only when transmitting HTTP (or HTTPS) requests, thus restricting access from other, non-HTTP APIs such as JavaScript). 

[source1](http://www.nczonline.net/blog/2009/05/05/http-cookies-explained/)

[source2](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
