<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Thoughts | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-28T22:28:20+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://okckd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Thoughts] My World]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/My-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-28T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/My-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[	Please tell me what is taking place,
	Cause I can't seem to find a trace,
	Guess it must've got erased somehow,
	Probably cause I always forget,
	Everytime someone tells me their name,
	It's always gotta be the same.
	(In my World)
	Never wore cover-up,
	Always beat the boys up,
	Grew up in a 5000 population town,
	Made my money by cutting grass,
	Got fired by fried chicken ass,
	All in a small town, Napanee.

	You know I always stay up without sleepin',
	And think to myself,
	Where do I belong forever,
	In whose arms, the time and place?

	[Chorus:]
	Can't help if I space in a daze,
	My eyes tune out the other way,
	I may switch off and go in a daydream,
	In this head my thoughts are deep,
	But sometimes I can't even speak,
	Would someone be and not pretend? 
	I'm off again in my World

	I never spend less than an hour,
	Washin' my hair in the shower,
	It always takes 5 hours to make it straight,
	So I'll braid it in a zillion braids,
	Though it may take all friggen day,
	There's nothin' else better to do anyway.

	When you're all alone in the lands of forever,
	Lay under the milky way,
	On and on it's getting too late out,
	I'm not in love this time this night.

	[Chorus:] x1

	Take some time,
	Mellow out,
	Party up,
	But don't fall down,
	Don't get caught,
	Sneak out of the house.

	[Chorus:] x2
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Thoughts] Ten Years Is a Long Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/Ten-years-is-a-long-time/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/Ten-years-is-a-long-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Life isn't always going along nicely. 

Remember this. 

Keep Holding On

	You're not alone, together we stand
	I'll be by your side you know I'll take your hand
	When it gets cold, and it feels like the end
	There's no place to go you know I won't give in
	(Ah, Ah) No I won't give in (Ah, Ah-Ah)

	Keep holding on
	'Cause you know we'll make it through
	We'll make it through

	Just stay strong
	'Cause you know I'm here for you
	I'm here for you

	There's nothing you can say (Nothing you can say)
	Nothing you could do (Nothing you could do)
	There's no other way when it comes to the truth so

	Keep holding on
	'Cause you know we'll make it through
	We'll make it through

	So far away, I wish you were here
	Before it's too late this could all disappear
	Before the doors close, and it comes to an end
	With you by my side I will fight and defend
	(Ah, Ah) I'll fight and defend (Ah, Ah-Ah) Yeah, Yeah

	Keep holding on (x1)

	Hear me when I say when I say "I believe"
	Nothing's gonna change nothing's gonna change destiny
	Whatever's meant to be will work out perfectly
	Yea-Eh, Yea-Eh, Yea-Eh, Yea-Eh-Ah-Ah (Ah-Ah, Ah-Ah)
	La-Da-Da-Da, La-Da-Da-Da, La-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da

	Keep holding on(x2)
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Thoughts] Some Random Thought]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/19/A-random-thought/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/08/19/A-random-thought</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[自从7月16号投了Fb，到今天一共33天。

我大概交了五六次简历。

一个面试都没有，妈的！ ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Thoughts] Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions IV]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/07/21/Thoughts-on-leetcode-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/07/21/Thoughts-on-leetcode-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Some stats

I started Leetcode __4 month ago__, and I took me around __2 month__ to finish most of the questions. I spent another __1 month__ to re-solve many questions, following the instructions from NineChap. Until 2 weeks ago, there're __in total 1861 submissions (or 18 submission per day)__.

From 2 weeks ago till today, I registed a new Leetcode account and solved __144/151 questions__ using __427 submission (or 35 submissions per day)__. I will probably finish up everything in 1 or 2 days' time. 

The AC/submission rate shall be used as a benchmark for future improvement. 

### Thoughts

Keep up the hard work! ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Thoughts] Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions III]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/06/01/thoughts-on-leetcode-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/06/01/thoughts-on-leetcode-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### First word

It's been around 2 month since I started doing Leetcode OJ, and a little more than a month since my first blog. 

__As of May 31st, 2014 Saturday__, I have solved __147/151 questions__ on LeetCode, plus __135 blog posts__. 

Unsolved questions are: 

1. Median of Two Sorted Arrays
2. Word Ladder II
3. Word Break II
4. LRU Cache

And while doing this, I also have a 9-to-5 job to feed myself. 

### Thoughts

I think this is a fruitful two months for me, from where I have struggled, compromised, grown, went sleepless, went crazy, went on fire and went exhausted from time to time, until I finally realize that I am beginning to see a bit of silver lining. But the more that I learn, the better that I understand how much more I am still lacking. 

I always thought this is gonna be a journey that takes me from one point to another, but __No__. It's not that simple. In the end, this might just be an infinitely long and tortuous journey that eventually take me to nowhere. But on the other hand, I never have believed in my entire life, that there's something in this world that I can't do. Sometimes hard work pays off, and sometimes good luck does. I always have both. And that gives me no reason to shrink. 

### Silver Lining

I suddenly remembered a great movie "__Silver Lining Playbook__" featuring Pat and Tiffany's difficult journey to happiness. 

> Pat: This is what I learned at the hospital. You have to do everything you can, you have to work your hardest, and if you do, you have a shot at a silver lining.

> Tiffany: Listen, I haven't dated since before my marriage so I don't really remember how this works. I saw the way you were looking at me, Pat. You felt it, I felt it, don't lie. We're not liars like they are. I live in the addition around back, which is completely separate from my parents' house, so there's no chance of them walking in on us. I hate the fact that you wore a football jersey to dinner because I hate football, but you can fuck me if you turn the lights off, okay?

> Tiffany: Humanity is just nasty and there's no silver lining.

> Tiffany: You know, for a while, I thought you were the best thing that ever happened to me. But now I'm starting to think you're the worst.

> Pat: The only way you can beat my crazy was by doing something crazy yourself. Thank you. I love you. I knew it the minute I met you. I'm sorry it took so long for me to catch up. I just got stuck.

I wish silvering lining will open up for me in the near future. 

And Happy Dragon Boat Festival, I just realize that. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
