<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Thoughts | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://okckd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-10T13:28:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://okckd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions IV]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/07/21/Thoughts-on-leetcode-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/07/21/Thoughts-on-leetcode-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### Some stats

I started Leetcode __4 month ago__, and I took me around __2 month__ to finish most of the questions. I spent another __1 month__ to re-solve many questions, following the instructions from NineChap. Until 2 weeks ago, there're __in total 1861 submissions (or 18 submission per day)__.

From 2 weeks ago till today, I registed a new Leetcode account and solved __144/151 questions__ using __427 submission (or 35 submissions per day)__. I will probably finish up everything in 1 or 2 days' time. 

The AC/submission rate shall be used as a benchmark for future improvement. 

### Thoughts

Keep up the hard work! ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions III]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/06/01/thoughts-on-leetcode-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/06/01/thoughts-on-leetcode-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### First word

It's been around 2 month since I started doing Leetcode OJ, and a little more than a month since my first blog. 

__As of May 31st, 2014 Saturday__, I have solved __147/151 questions__ on LeetCode, plus __135 blog posts__. 

Unsolved questions are: 

1. Median of Two Sorted Arrays
2. Word Ladder II
3. Word Break II
4. LRU Cache

And while doing this, I also have a 9-to-5 job to feed myself. 

### Thoughts

I think this is a fruitful two months for me, from where I have struggled, compromised, grown, went sleepless, went crazy, went on fire and went exhausted from time to time, until I finally realize that I am beginning to see a bit of silver lining. But the more that I learn, the better that I understand how much more I am still lacking. 

I always thought this is gonna be a journey that takes me from one point to another, but __No__. It's not that simple. In the end, this might just be an infinitely long and tortuous journey that eventually take me to nowhere. But on the other hand, I never have believed in my entire life, that there's something in this world that I can't do. Sometimes hard work pays off, and sometimes good luck does. I always have both. And that gives me no reason to shrink. 

### Silver Lining

I suddenly remembered a great movie "__Silver Lining Playbook__" featuring Pat and Tiffany's difficult journey to happiness. 

> Pat: This is what I learned at the hospital. You have to do everything you can, you have to work your hardest, and if you do, you have a shot at a silver lining.

> Tiffany: Listen, I haven't dated since before my marriage so I don't really remember how this works. I saw the way you were looking at me, Pat. You felt it, I felt it, don't lie. We're not liars like they are. I live in the addition around back, which is completely separate from my parents' house, so there's no chance of them walking in on us. I hate the fact that you wore a football jersey to dinner because I hate football, but you can fuck me if you turn the lights off, okay?

> Tiffany: Humanity is just nasty and there's no silver lining.

> Tiffany: You know, for a while, I thought you were the best thing that ever happened to me. But now I'm starting to think you're the worst.

> Pat: The only way you can beat my crazy was by doing something crazy yourself. Thank you. I love you. I knew it the minute I met you. I'm sorry it took so long for me to catch up. I just got stuck.

I wish silvering lining will open up for me in the near future. 

And Happy Dragon Boat Festival, I just realize that. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions II]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/Thoughts-on-leetcode-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/Thoughts-on-leetcode-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### First word

__As of May 18th, 2014 Sunday__, I have solved __120/151 questions__ on LeetCode, plus __60+ blog posts__.

### Thoughts 

When I started doing LeetCode and try to come up with solutions, I was generally good in productivity. But recently as I start to read other people's code and try to find the best solution from the internet, I started to slow down my pace. I thought it's a good thing, because reading other people's code helps me to diverse my thinking. As a matter of fact, it really is good. However, as the number of difficult problems start to increase, I am starting to face some bottleneck with productivity. I am sometimes stuck in 1 problem for 2+ hours, and sometime I start to be bored at reading code. Maybe it's the lack of sleep, I would feel dizzy sometimes doing LeetCode. I am sure that my passion in keep doing this has never decreased, but maybe I was just trying to hard. 

__Keep in mind that learning is not always as exciting as the first few days__, and keep holding on. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on LeetCode Questions]]></title>
    <link href="http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/05/09/Thoughts-on-leetcode/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://okckd.github.io/blog/2014/05/09/Thoughts-on-leetcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[### First word

__May 8th, 2014 Thursday is the historical day that a milestone is set__. I have solved more than 100 questions on leetcode!

The past 2 month have been a great training opportunity for my programming skills, and I shall definitely keep up this work. 

### Thoughts 

1. __Practice makes perfect__. Code implementation is simply a matter of experience and practice. Some questions is easy in algorithm but hard in writing code (eg. atoi). This skill is gained, not taught, so I will focus less in coding implementation in future posts. 

2. __There is just a handful of algorithms in this world__, and most question can be solved with the most standard algorithms. Keep in mind these algorithms is important. 

3. __There are sometimes brain teaser questions__ like Single Number II or Sort Colors. These question really needs a intelligent brain. 


This is all I have right now. Will update later. 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
